case.org 2019-12-04

# CASE Privacy Statement & Policy | CASE

## Last updated January 4, 2019

The Council for Advancement and Support of Education is a nonprofit membership association serving educational institutions and the advancement professionals who work on their behalf in alumni relations, communications, development, marketing and allied areas. CASE helps its members build stronger relationships with their alumni and donors, raise funds for campus projects, produce recruitment materials, market their institutions to prospective students, diversify the profession, and foster public support of education.

CASE helps its members build stronger relationships with all of their constituencies by providing relevant research, supporting growth in the profession and fostering support of education.

CASE also offers a variety of advancement products and services, provides standards and an ethical framework for the profession, and works with other organizations to respond to public issues of concern while promoting the importance of education worldwide.

This Privacy Statement (the 'Statement') explains the personal information we collect from you, either directly or indirectly, and how we use it. Personal information is any information that can be used to identify you or that can be linked to you. The Statement also covers the choices you can make about the data we collect, and how you can control these decisions. It applies to all products and services offered by CASE. It also applies to any CASE-controlled websites (including [www.case.org](https://www.case.org/)) or mobile apps that link to this Statement, as well as other interactions with CASE, such as attending a CASE event. Please read this Statement carefully to understand how CASE may collect, use, and share your personal information. The terms 'we', 'us', or 'CASE' are each intended as reference to the Council for Advancement and Support of Education.

**Information you provide to us**  
In order to use certain features of the CASE website, a user must first complete a registration form. During registration, users will be asked to provide contact information, such as name and email address, phone number, institutional affiliation, and job title. This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they may have expressed interest. It will be optional for the user to provide additional information, such as demographic information or other personal information so that we can provide a more personalized experience.

Whenever you place an order via the site, on the phone or by mail, or register for a conference, information will be requested on an order form. The information requested includes name and shipping address as well as financial information such as a payment card number and expiration date. This information is used for billing purposes and to fill orders. (Please note that CASE does not store payment card information in its databases except for the expiration date and the last four digits of the card).

We collect information you voluntarily provide to us, such as your name, phone number and email address; for instance, when you want to learn more about CASE membership, products or educational opportunities, or when you contact our membership support center for assistance. We may collect this information through surveys and benchmarking studies.

**Information we collect automatically**  
We automatically collect information about you through the use of cookies and similar technologies when you use, access or interact with us via our websites or apps. We use this information to automate certain aspects of our website, to "remember" you when you enter our site, to track your preferences, geographic location and to retain any personalization you've done to enhance your experience with CASE.

**Information obtained from other sources**  
We may, on occasion, receive information about you from other sources, including third parties, such as partners with whom we offer co-branded conferences or engage in joint marketing activities. We may also receive information about you from social media platforms, for instance, when you interact with us on those platforms. We protect data obtained from third parties according to the practices described in this Statement and we also apply any additional restrictions imposed by the source of data.

We may also engage third parties to serve the advertisements that appear on our Web site and within other parts of the CASE interface. These companies may use cookies to ensure you do not see the same advertisements too often, and these cookies also may collect information about you when you view or click on an advertisement. Such ad-serving companies are responsible for placing and reading these cookies; we do not have access to these cookies or control how they are used.

**Supplemental Information**  
CASE supplements the information you provide with information that is received from third parties. For example, we may include in your profile data supplied by the institution at which you are employed.

In addition to the use of cookies as described above, we use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website. Your IP address is used to help identify you and your preferences and to gather broad demographic information.

We use the information you provide about yourself when ordering a product or service, registering for a conference, or becoming a CASE member in order to complete the transaction. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete the transaction.

We use the information we collect based on usage by those who register with the CASE website to customize the information on the site to the user's interests.

We use the information you provide about yourself for the online membership directory for a variety of organizational purposes, including sharing with you information about CASE products and services we think might be of interest to you. CASE also uses personal information for advertising and marketing purposes, such as by sending offers for products and services that we think will be of interest to you.

Finally, we do not intend to use or share the personal information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you with an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

**Public Forums**  
The website makes interest or group-based communities available to its users. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes available to other members of the group and you should therefore exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

We offer postal mailing lists for rent to third parties. On occasion we may send an email communication to our members on behalf of a third party, but we do not share email addresses with external organizations or individuals without consent.

CASE uses a variety of third-party vendors to carry out services like website and database management and hosting, online product shipping, credit card processing and email communications. We only share your personal information as needed, such as to complete a transaction or to provide a product or service you have requested. In this case, your personal information will be shared with these agents or contractors but only for the purpose of performing services on behalf of CASE and in accordance with this Statement. It is our legitimate interest to share information with these parties for these purposes.

We use data gathered through surveys and benchmarking studies solely for the purposes described therein. Unless specifically noted otherwise, no personal information is disclosed in reporting on these surveys and studies. We may also share your personal information as part of a corporate sale, merger, or acquisition, or other transfer of all or part of our assets including as part of a bankruptcy proceeding; pursuant to a subpoena, court order, governmental inquiry, or other legal process or as otherwise required by law, or to protect our rights or the rights of third parties; or with your consent or as otherwise disclosed at the time of data collection or sharing.

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and other CASE services. We also may share such information with associations, organizations and commercial enterprises to help them understand the makeup of the CASE membership.

**Performance of a contract**  
The relationship between CASE and its member institutions is such that in order to fulfill the obligations related to membership, it is necessary for us to process personal information related to the employees of our member institutions who participate in our programs. This relationship also extends to individuals who are not employed by member institutions but who have willingly entered into a relationship with us, for example, by registering for a conference or purchasing a product.

**Security**  
CASE takes reasonable precautions to guard the personal information we collect, but please be advised that no system is impenetrable.

We use a variety of appropriate technical and organizational measures and industry standards to protect your personal information and help prevent information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems that have limited access and are in controlled facilities. In addition, we ensure that our third-party data center vendors provide adequate security measures. Moreover, your password is stored using one-way hash, which means that it cannot be recovered (or disclosed) by anyone, including CASE.

You can only access your CASE account information through the use of an individual user login and password. To protect the confidentiality of your personal information, keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. Please alert us immediately if you believe your password has been misused. Additionally, always log out and close your browser when you finish your session. Please note, we will never ask you to disclose your password.

**Storage**  
Personal information collected by CASE may be stored and processed in your region, in the United States (for instance in our data center), or in any other country where CASE or its service providers are located or maintain facilities. CASE has put in place adequate mechanisms to protect personal information when it is transferred internationally, for example by using the Standard Contractual Clauses as approved by the European Commission.

**Retention**  
CASE will retain your personal information for as long as necessary to enable you to engage with CASE relative to your organization's membership or your participation in CASE activities, to provide services to you, to comply with audit requirements (including those regarding document retention), resolve disputes with any parties and otherwise as necessary to allow us to conduct our business. All personal information we retain will be subject to this Privacy Statement and our internal retention guidelines.

**Your Rights**  
Subject to local law, you may have the following rights over your personal information:

  * You can ask us for a copy of the personal information we hold about you;
  * You can inform us of any changes to your personal information, or if you want us to correct any of the personal information we hold about you;
  * In certain situations, you can ask us to erase, block or restrict the personal information we hold about you, or object to particular ways in which we are using your personal information; and
  * In certain situations, you can also ask us to provide you with a copy of your personal information in a machine-readable format or provide that copy to a third party.

When we use your personal information on the basis of your consent, you are entitled to withdraw that consent at any time.

We rely on you to ensure that your personal information is complete, accurate and current. Please inform us promptly of any changes to, or inaccuracies in your personal information by submitting a [ticket to Member Support](http://support.case.org/) via the "[Ask CASE](https://www.case.org/Ask_CASE.html)" section of our website.

We will respond to your request as soon as possible but certainly within 30 days. For more information about how you can control your Communication, Marketing and Advertising Preferences, please visit the "Your Choices" section below.

We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern you may have about our use of your personal information. If, however, you believe that we have not been able to assist with your complaint or concern, you may have the right to lodge a complaint with the data protection authority in your country (if one exists in your country).

**CASE Account**  
If you wish to access, edit or remove profile information or change your password, you can do it by logging in to your CASE account by submitting a ticket to ticket.case.org. If you wish to request deletion of your personal information, please [submit a ticket to Member Support](http://support.case.org/) via the "[Ask CASE](https://www.case.org/Ask_CASE.html)" section of our website. We will respond to any request to access or delete your personal information as soon as possible but certainly within 30 days.

**Your Communication, Marketing and Advertising Preferences**  
You can opt out of receiving direct marketing communications from CASE by following the instructions included in every email sent to you via the "Unsubscribe" tab. We respect your choice, and we will stop sending you promotional emails once you unsubscribe or change your communication settings.

Please note, regardless of your communication settings, we will continue to communicate with you regarding changes to your organization's membership, routine customer service messages such as information about current or past purchase, delivery of products, service interruptions, data breaches or other significant information that may impact you directly.

We adhere to the Digital Advertising Alliance ("DAA") Self-Regulatory Principles in connection with interest-based advertising activities. You may visit the DAA Webchoices tool at [www.aboutads.info](https://www.aboutads.info/) to learn more about this type of advertising and how to opt out of it on websites by companies participating in the DAA self-regulatory program. If you delete your cookies or use a different browser or mobile device, you may need to renew your opt-out choices exercised through the DAA Webchoices tool. Note that electing to opt out will not stop advertising from appearing in your browser or applications. It may make the ads you see less relevant to your interests. Additionally, your browser may offer tools to limit the use of cookies or to delete cookies; however, if you use these tools, our website may not function as intended.

We use cookies and similar technologies to help us personalize our websites for you, remember your preferences, understand how users are using our websites, and to help customize our offerings.

**Cookies**  
A 'cookie' is a small data file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website. When you visit the website again, the cookie allows that site to recognize your browser. The length of time a cookie will stay on your computer or mobile device depends on whether it is a "persistent" or "session" cookie. CASE uses both types of cookies. Session cookies will only stay on your device until you stop browsing. Persistent cookies stay on your computer or mobile device until they expire or are deleted. We use the following types of cookies on our website.

  * Strictly necessary cookies. These cookies are essential for you to browse our website and use its features. Without these cookies, services like shopping baskets cannot be provided.
  * Performance cookies. These cookies collect information about how you use our websites. This data may be used to help optimize our website and make it easier for you to navigate.
  * Functional cookies. These cookies allow our websites to remember choices you make and personalize your experience. We may store your geographic location in a cookie, for instance, to ensure that we show you what is relevant to your area.
  * Third Party cookies. Third-party cookies are those placed by websites and/or parties other than CASE. These cookies may be used on our websites to improve our products or services or to help us provide more relevant advertising. These cookies are subject to the respective privacy policies for these external services.
  * Analytics cookies. We use analytics cookies, like those offered by Google Analytics, to help us understand things like how long a visitor stays on our websites, what pages they find most useful and how they arrived at our website. To learn more about Google Analytics and your data, [visit this Google webpage](https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies?hl=en).

**How to Control Cookie Settings**  
Most web browsers allow you to control cookies through their settings preferences. However, if you limit the ability of websites to set cookies, you may impact your overall user experience. Please refer to the cookie control settings on your browser for more information on how to manage your cookies.

**Advertising and Marketing Tools**  
CASE may work with third-party advertisers that use cookies and similar technologies to provide more relevant advertising about CASE Products and Services on our website and across the internet. To provide this 'interest-based advertising', the parties combine non-personal information about your online activities acquired over time, which help personalize advertising that we deliver to you. We do not share your personal information as part of this process. Where necessary we obtain your consent to this process.

We may also work with third parties that collect data about your use of our website and other websites or apps over time for non-advertising purposes. Among these third parties, we may use Google to improve the performance of our website and for analytics and marketing purposes. For more information about how Google Analytics collects and uses data when you use our website, visit https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/, and to opt out of Google Analytics, visit[ https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). 

If you have any questions about the use of your personal information or any aspects of this Statement, please submit a ticket to Member Support via the "Ask CASE" section of our website. You may also contact one of our regional offices directly, each a data controller, listed below:

**CASE US and Canada**  
1307 New York Ave., N.W.  
Suite 1000  
Washington, DC 20005-4701  
+1 202-328-2273

**CASE Europe and Africa**  
3rd Floor, Paxton House  
30 Artillery Lane  
London E1 7LS  
+44 20 7448 9940

**CASE Asia-Pacific**  
11 Kent Ridge Drive  
Unit 05-03, Shaw Foundation Alumni House  
Singapore 119244  
+65- 6778 3286

**CASE Latin America and the Caribbean**  
Berlín 18 4to piso, Colonia Juárez  
Código Postal 06600, México D.F.  
Delegación Cuauhtémoc, Mexico  
+52 (55) 27091577

CASE may modify or update this Statement when necessary to reflect changes to international law and policy. Please review it regularly. When we update this Statement, we will revise the 'Last Updated' date at the top of the Statement. If there are material changes to the Statement or in how CASE uses your personal information, we will notify you either by posting a notice of such changes before they take effect or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to regularly review this Statement to learn more how CASE is using and protecting your information.

## FAQS

We will update our privacy statement as necessary to ensure that our policies are in line with international regulations and business practices.

CASE collects contact information, such as name and email address, phone number, institutional affiliation, and job title. This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they may have expressed interest. It will be optional for the user to provide additional information, such as demographic information or other personal information so that we can provide a more personalized experience. In addition, CASE collects shipping address, payment information, location data, IP address, social identifiers, data provided by cookies and similar technologies, and functional data such as registration and system data.

CASE uses the data we collect to fulfill the obligations of membership and provide you the best experience within products and services we offer, which includes using data to improve and personalize your experiences. We also use the data to communicate with you, for example, informing you about your membership, new products or services available, security and other types of updates.

CASE uses the data we collect for the following purposes:

  * To fulfill membership obligations
  * Product and services improvement
  * Future product and services development
  * Membership and customer support
  * Product and services performance analysis
  * Communications and marketing of CASE products and services
  * Industry research

We use the information to make sure that we are offering you the right product and service options based on your geographic location, your institution type and size, and your particular areas of interest.

CASE offers postal mailing lists for rent to third parties. On occasion, we may send email communications to our members on behalf of external organizations or individuals.

Yes, you can opt out of submitting certain types of personal information to CASE. However, certain categories of the data that we collect, referred to as functional data, are necessary for CASE to perform its basic functions in a secure way and you will not be able to opt out.

You can always contact our Member Support team and request that your data be deleted. Please note, however, that by deleting your personal information your will be unable to receive the benefits or membership, purchase CASE products, or participate in CASE events.

No. Credit card information is tokenized within CASE systems and not stored except for the last 4 digits.

CASE retains personal information for as long as necessary to provide the services, support your membership and fulfill the transactions you have requested, or for other essential purposes such as complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes and enforcing our agreements. Because these needs can vary for different data types in the context of different products or services, actual retention periods can vary.

CASE is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems that have limited access and are in controlled facilities.

Yes, we use cookies and similar technologies when you visit our website. By visiting our website, you agree to the use of cookies and similar technologies for the purposes we describe in our privacy statement. This helps us provide you with the best experience and allows certain parts of our website to function properly. You can always adjust your browser or device settings to not accept cookies and similar technologies if this concerns you.

Yes. We work with third-party advertisers that utilize cookies and similar technologies to provide more relevant advertising on our website and across the internet. To provide interest-based advertising, the advertisers combine non-personal information learned about your online activities over time to customize the advertising delivered to you.
